Franziska Hammerl

Web Developer

Located in Berlin, relocating to Spain summer 2023



https://github.com/ZHammerl

https://zhammerl.github.io/portfolio-website/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/franziska-hammerl



PROFILE

Creative and solution-oriented web developer, experienced in identifying and implementing opportunities for improved efficiency and reduced cost, with a neverstop-learning attitude and skilled in collaborating with interdisciplinary teams. Able to build responsive applications from scratch (desktop and mobile), using JavaScript both on the server side with Node.js and Express to build APIs, and to create complex UI on the client side using frameworks such as Angular and React.

SKILLS & TOOLS

Front-End:

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript
- Angular, React (Redux, Router)
- Responsive Design
- MUI, Angular Material, Bootstrap, SASS/SCSS
- Version Control (GIT)
- Test & Behavior-Driven-Development (unit, integration, acceptance and endto-end testing)
- Functional & Object-Oriented-Programming
- Mobile Apps (React Native, Expo, PWA)

Back-End:

- NodeJS & Express
- APIs (JSON, RESTful, Postman)
- Hosting & Web Services (AWS, Firestore, Heroku, Netlify)
- Relational & Non-relational databases: PostgreSQL, MondoDB

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development CareerFoundry GmbH | 2022-2023

• Intense project-based training program

- focused on MERN stack
- 500+ hours of hands-on training with guidance of industry leading tutor and

MSc International Business & Enterprise University of South Wales, UK | 2017-2018

BA Tourism Business Management Management Center Innsbruck | 2010-2013

WORLD LANGUAGES

German: native speaker

English: fluent Spanisch: fluent

WEB DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

FULL-STACK PROJECT | CareerFoundry | MyFlix

- Created non-relational database (MongoDB)
- Built a **RESTful API using NodeJS and Express**, using Mongoose to interact with the database
- Used Postman to test API endpoints, deplyoyed API to Heroku
- Built two responsive SPAs, one with React (following MVC design pattern) and one with **Angular** (using Angular Material)
- Users can set up, edit and delete their accounts, browse movie library, add a favorite movie to their profile and get more information on directors and genres

Anuglar client demo | Angular github respository React client demo | React github repository

FULL-STACK PROJECT | CareerFoundry | Meet App

- Developed a responsive, serverless PWA (offline availability, cross-platform) using React to display events from a google calendar
- Followed TDD approach, translating user stories into scenarios for unit and integration tests (Jest), acceptance testing (cucumber) and end-to-end testing (puppeteer)
- Implemented serverless functions (AWS Lambda) to authenticate and authorize users (OAuth)
- Used Kanban board following agile process

Meet App demo | Meet App github repository

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Office and Culture Manager

Jul 2020 - May 2022

Made of Air GmbH | Berlin | ClimateTech Start-up

- Oversaw recruitment, assisting in rapid growth from 9 to 22 staff members, serving in various roles, incl. recruiter, HR representative, team assistant, bookkeeper, and travel manager.
- Orchestrated several team events and an office relocation.
- Assessed and implemented enterprise software for bookkeeping, HR management, and project management, resulting in significant improvements in efficiency and organization.
- Built low-code invoice approval workflow app with MS PowerApps and synced it with MS Sharepoint Intranet for further process automation.

Customer Service

Aug 2018 - Aug 2019

ADM Wild Netherlands | Amsterdam | Food & Beverage Multinational

- Negotiated with logistics providers to reduce costs and improve delivery times
- Led invoicing process digitalization efforts for efficiency gains of approx. 2 days

Order and Delivery Planning

Nov 2015 - Dec 2016

Endel de Mexico | Queretaro, MX | Engineering Multinational

- Optimized order-to-delivery process, reducing turnaround times by 48 hours
- Acted as primary liaison with international departments